原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     高庭玫瑰   春天里的小熊   肉塔   轩辕喵
翻译     徐棒棒   木浅   GV   匡老师   ABCpril    PiPi
校对   丶何何丶 不高兴童鞋  木浅   普利星布里狗
时间轴     姜姜    大葱    壬虚浪影    WEB版轴  何何丶
后期     吉吉    V2版后期  丶胜天半子丶的丶何何丶
总监     & 精校       丶胜天半子丶的丶何何丶
越狱     我命由我不由天！胜天半子半痴癫！
人人影视Pro
人人影视官方唯一APP
在线观看，离线缓存，百度云
app.YYeTs.com
官方网站下载 : 人人影视Pro
越 狱 第五季第九集
《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break...
我们找到迈克尔了
We found Michael.
没想到还能再见到你
Never thought I'd see this face again.
你本不该见到的
You weren't supposed to.
我欠你的  斯科菲尔德
I own you, Scofield.
如果你在蓄谋什么
If you're planning something,
我总是会先你一步的
I'll always be a step ahead of you.
你老公
Your husband.
雅各布就是波塞冬
Jacob is Poseidon.
他是中情局特工
He's a CIA operative,
深度卧底
deep cover.
他管理着一个叫做"21号空间"的地下组织
He runs a splinter cell called 21-Void.
扫描已启动
身份匹配已获取
他看中了我的能力
He targeted me for my skills.
四年前  他背叛了我  这样就能拥有你了
Four years ago, he betrayed me so he could have you.
他是怎么背叛你的
How did he betray you?
我们原本要去见中情局副局长
We were meeting a man named Harlan Gaines,
哈伦·盖恩斯
a deputy director of the CIA.
可波塞冬当晚却射杀了盖恩斯
Poseidon shot and killed Gaines that night.
我当时就知道自己被下套了
I knew I was being set up.
迈克尔  他现在正和我们的儿子在一起
Michael, he's with our son right now.
当时斯科菲尔德在各个监狱里搜寻搭档
Scofield was looking for a partner, combing prisons,
想找一个独自生存能力强的人
looking for someone who could handle himself.
你到底想说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
这是你与生俱来的  孩子  是我传给你的
It was ingrained in you, son. You got it from me.
这张截图来自他从沙漠发出的聊天视频
Screen grab of the Skype transmission he sent from the desert.
有那么多信息可以加密  为什么选这个
Of all things to encrypt, why that?
干完这次我就退出"21号空间"
I'm done with 21-Void after this.
没人能离开"21号空间"  梵
There's no leaving 21-Void, Van.
闭上嘴直接把钱给我怎样  布鲁斯
How about you just shut up and pay me, Burrows?
我没钱
I don't have it.
你知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
我会救你和你妈妈出去
I'm gonna get you and your mother out of here.
我们得快跑
We need to run.
六分钟前
你知道自己是精神病吗
Do you know that you're a psychopath?
我敢说  我不是第一个对家人隐瞒身份的
I assure you, I'm not the first CIA man to hide his life
中情局特工
from his family.
你隐瞒的可是中情局
You hid it from the CIA.
你想把事情搞砸
Look, you want to screw something up?
那就码一千个人来做  你想把事做对
Put a thousand people on it. You want to get it done right?
那就找几个精英  我们一直以来所做的事
Put it in the hands of a few. What we were doing
就是推进这个国家的伟业
was advancing this country's cause.
把阿布·拉马尔这种人放出来
How does freeing a man like Abu Ramal
是怎么推进国家伟业的
advance this country's cause?
好吧  确实不是
Well, it doesn't.
之前的任务
The missions before,
都是为了这个国家好  但是...
they were for the good of the country, but...
不  这件事跟国家没有关系
No, this one wasn't about country.
跟你有关
It was about you.
没有人想要为了过去的生活奋不顾身  莎拉
Nobody wants to die to their old life, Sara.
迈克尔可不这样
And Michael didn't.
他极其渴望自己能把握住过去
He wanted to hold on to it so desperately.
就在那一刻  我想让他消失
In that moment, I wanted him to go away,
放弃和他的整个协议  只要我能拥有你
the whole agreement, and just have you.
你把他派到也门去送死
You sent him to Yemen to die.
我一直告诉自己这是我的最后一个谎言
Kept telling myself this was gonna be my last lie.
会随着我们的每一个周年纪念
That it would fade with time as we had anniversaries,
和共同抚养我们可爱的孩子而消逝
raised that beautiful child.
那不是你的孩子
That is not your child.
我抚养了他
I raised him.
那份爱是真的
That love is real.
那不是谎言
It's not a lie.
你在把他当作诱饵
You are using him as bait.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
她知道不能伤害他
She knows not to hurt him.
你纠结于迈克尔不放
You were so obsessed with Michael
不惜置我的儿子于危险之中
that you would risk my son!
迈克尔吗  你是说你吧
Michael? You mean you.
你并不爱我  你太自我了
You don't love me. Your ego's too big.
你一心只想要成为最聪明的人
You're too busy trying to be the smartest man in the room.
然后你遇到了我丈夫
And then you met my husband,
你意识到
and you realized
他比你聪明
he's smarter than you.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
你确定吗
You sure?
我很确定
I'm positive.
我们的爱是真的  莎拉
Our love was real, Sara.
过去式而已
Past tense.
我还爱你
I still love you.
一切就绪  头儿
Everything's set, boss.
好的
Good.
得算你一份功劳
Got to give you credit.
你会不惜一切代价帮一个人
You'll go the whole nine yards to help one man
抢另一个人的老婆
steal another man's wife.
不不不  别跟他说话
No, no, no. Don't talk to him.
否则会怎样  他会做一些
Or what? He'll do something
你不打算要做的事吗  你会杀了我
you're not already gonna do? You're going to kill me.
不管你先跟我说多少次你爱我
No matter how many times you tell me you love me first.
闭嘴
Shut up!
哈伦·盖恩斯不是迈克尔杀的  他没有动机
Michael didn't kill Harlan Gaines. He had no motive.
-闭嘴  -他才是那个有杀人动机的人
- Shut up. - He's the one with the motive.
哈伦·盖恩斯曾是你在中情局的局长
Harlan Gaines was your CIA director
他在调查雅各布
and he was looking into Jacob.
他本来要把他关进监狱
He was gonna put him prison.
该死
Damn it!
麻烦用胶带把她的嘴封起来
Tape her mouth shut, please.
封起来
Tape it shut.
如果你这么做  就会害死一个无辜的人
If you do, an innocent man dies,
而放走真正的凶手
and the real killer walks.
你还不明白吗
Don't you understand?
是雅各布杀了哈伦·盖恩斯
Jacob killed Harlan Gaines.
闭嘴吧你
Just shut it.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
1号监控摄像头 - 前方
他来了  是时候了
Here he comes. It's time to do this.
这个地方会在十分钟后烧毁
This place is gonna burn down in ten minutes.
里面会有两具尸体
There will be two bodies in it.
如果这算是安慰的话
And if it's any solace,
我们的儿子不会是其中之一
our son won't be one of them.
山中无老虎  猴子称大王
While the cat's away, the mice will play.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
我收到了你的地图
I got your map.
我会救你和你妈妈出去
I'm gonna get you and your mother out of here.
我没画过地图
I didn't draw a map.
我们得快跑
We need to run.
等一下
Wait.
你上来做什么  梵
What are you doing up here, Van?
我就想确定我们抓对人了
I just want to make sure that we're getting the right guy.
问他一些问题
Ask him some questions.
放了我儿子
Let my son go.
我任凭你们处置
Do whatever you want with me.
只要你们放我儿子走
Just let my son go.
命令不是让我们不该问的也问
Orders weren't to ask questions.
而是格杀勿论
It was to shoot on sight.
或许我们应该问几个问题  妈的
Maybe we should ask questions, damn it.
如果斯科菲尔德杀了哈伦·盖恩斯
If Scofield killed Harlan Gaines,
必要时我们可以把他交给警方
we take him to the police, if we have to.
我们应该用正当的途径解决
We get this done the right way.
波塞冬不会放过我们的
Poseidon would never let us live.
他不会找到我们的
He won't find us.
我跟你说过  我们想销声匿迹就一定可以
I told you. We want to disappear, we disappear.
我能做得到的
I can make that happen.
我们把他交给警方
We turn him in,
然后就走人
and we're gone.
别逼我做这样的选择
Don't make me choose like this.
艾米丽
Emily.
我们果真有的选吗
Is it really even a choice?
没有
No.
因为没人能离开"21号空间"
'Cause there's no leaving 21-Void.
快走  你伯伯在车道尽头
Go. Your uncle's at the end of the driveway.
别回头  跑  快
Don't turn around. Run! Go!
莎拉
Sara.
我们儿子在哪
Where's our boy?
林肯伯伯  林肯伯伯
Uncle Lincoln, Uncle Lincoln!
不  不  是我  发生什么事了
No, no, no, it's me. What's going on?
有人在开枪  我很害怕
They're shooting. I'm scared.
-他们是来抓你的  -谁
- Okay. They've come for you. - ‭Who?
我不会让他们伤害你
I am not gonna let them hurt you,
明白吗  上车
you understand? Get in the car.
我们现在就得走  麦克  现在就走
No, we've got to go now, Mike. We've got to go.
妈妈怎么办呢
What about my mom?
走  走  走
Go, go, go.
麦克
Mike!
麦克  不
Mike! No!
不
No!
麦克
Mike!
他抓走了他
He took him.
-莎拉  -他抓走了我们的儿子
- Sara... - ‭He took our son.
冷静  冷静  亲爱的
Come back to me. Come back to me, sweetheart.
冷静下来
Come back to me.
我们得集中注意力  好吗
We got to stay focused, all right?
这事还没完  很大程度上还没完
This is not over. Not by a long shot.
-林肯在哪  -什么
- Where's Linc? - ‭What?
我们得找到林肯  好吗
We got to find Linc, okay?
我们得找到林肯
We're gonna find Linc.
林肯
Linc.
天啊
Oh my God.
林肯  林肯
Linc. Linc.
我让你失望了  迈克尔
I let you down, Michael.
我当时本该抓住时机解决卢卡
I should have taken care of Luca when I had the chance.
你没让我失望  你当时也料不到会这样
You didn't let me down. You couldn't have known.
多亏了你  我们快成功了  哥
We're so close because of you, Linc.
是你把我救回家的
You got me home.
是你
他们稳定他的伤势了  迈克尔
They've stabilized him, Michael.
我们也帮不上什么了
There's nothing we can do.
我们现在还是赶快离开吧
We've got to get you out of here right now.
你得给我点人生建议  知道不
Okay, you got to give me some direction here, you know?
一些...
Some, um...
父辈的建议
fatherly advice
怎样和你这样的父亲...
on how to deal with having a father that's, um...
相处
you.
好吧  你知道...
Well, you know, uh...
你是不是和我一样  看见这瓶子血就抓狂
Is this blood freaking you out like it's freaking me out?
对啊  对啊  我来...
Yeah, yeah. Let me, uh...
迈克尔说完成这件事会让我们都得到救赎
Scofield said that it would deliver me. Both of us.
我所需要做的
All I have to do
就是把血带给他
is just get it to him.
我明白其中缘由
I understand why.
所以我才能最后明白这句话
So I can finally understand this.
他给你的吗
He give you this?
"经汝之手  晓'后史'之荣耀"
"By your hand, you shall know the glories of your progeny..."
不对  不对...
I-It's, it's...
是"后世"  孩子
It's "Progeny," Dear boy.
"后世"
"Progeny."
"吾等世界终将拨乱反正  永垂不朽"
"And our world will be made right forevermore."
最初  我觉得这事和宗教有关
Originally, I thought it was a religious thing.
上帝之子啊什么的
You know, son of God, and all that.
但现在我明白...
But now I know it's...
这句话就是对我说的
it's my own progeny.
而你
You.
就是我遇到的真正美好的事
It's a glorious thing indeed.
就算我现在不知道该怎么处理我们的关系
Even if I don't have a damn clue how to deal with it.
彼此彼此
You and me both.
我有个把我们儿子救回来的办法  莎拉
I've got a way to get our son back, Sara.
自从他逼迫我疏远你和麦克
I've been planning to bring Jacob down
我就一直在计划如何扳倒雅各布
ever since he forced me to turn my back on you and Mike.
自从我进了也门监狱
A plan I had to put on hold
这个计划就搁浅了
while I was in that Yemeni prison.
我必须要等到从监狱逃出来
I had to wait till I got out.
等到万事俱备的时候
Till everything aligned.
等到现在  才能执行
Till now.
告诉我你有结果了
Tell me you got something.
差点逃过了我的眼睛
It's eluding me.
在眼睛里有更深一层的编码
There's an even bigger code encrypted into the eyes.
内容是什么
And what's it say?
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
按照我现在的破解速度
But with the amount of processing power I throw at it,
我们很快就会有结果的
we're gonna find out real soon.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不知道该怎么告诉你
I-I don't know how to say it, so, um...
刚才那个人是个警探
That man was a police detective,
他刚刚告诉我  你妈...
and he told me your moth...
你妈死了
your mother's dead.
什么
What?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
不过我会带你去一个安全的地方
But I'm gonna take you somewhere safe,
在那里  没有人能伤害你  也没人能找到你
where those people that are trying to hurt you can't reach you.
为什么会有人想伤害我呢
Why would they try and hurt me?
这是因为我爱你
It's because I love you.
而这些人想伤害我
And they're trying to hurt me--
所以他们才会伤害我最爱的人
take the one thing that I truly love away.
那他们为什么想伤害你
Why would they try and hurt you?
这是因为有一些关于我的事我还没告诉你
Because there are some things I haven't told you about me.
我给你寄那封信是有原因的
I sent that letter to you for a reason.
波塞冬当时正在监视
Poseidon was monitoring my communications
一切对我可能有利的资源或者盟友
with everyone who could possibly be a resource or an ally,
但没有监视曾被我鄙视的人
but not with people I despised.
直说吧  你到底怎么看我这个人
Give it to me straight-- how you really feel about me?
我想过  如果我给予一个人
I figured if I showed grace to a man
他此生从未体验过的恩惠
who'd never seen it before in his life,
或许他会为了表达感激
maybe he'd be grateful,
而为我们做一些事情
do something for us.
为我们所有人
All of us,
也包括为他自己
himself included.
"吾等世界终将拨乱反正  永垂不朽"
"And our lives shall be made right forevermore."
我是指普通人的生活
I'm talking about normal, everyday life.
一种我们很久很久
The kind of freedom none of us has known
没有体验过的生活
in a long, long time.
但波塞冬并不想放过我们
But Poseidon's not just gonna let us go.
他将我和你儿子牢牢控制在其股掌之中
He's got me and your son in an iron grip.
必须得有人让他罢手
Someone has to make him let go.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
我完全理解你的意思
I'm tracking where you're going.
可以使我们过上你说的那种
Only way we're gonna get that
美好而又普通生活的唯一方法
beautiful, mundane life you're talking-- any of us--
就是我杀了他
is if I take his.
我们暂时安全了
We'll be safe here for now.
听着
Hey, listen,
我保证我会跟你解释一切
I promised I'd explain.
那些人在追杀我的原因
The reason those people are after me...
我明白  对你来说会很难相信
I know this is gonna be hard to believe,
但简单来说  我是一个秘密特工
but I'm basically a secret agent.
扫描已启动
图像采集
快进来
Come on in.
你记得你在后院里的城堡吗
You know that fort you've got in the backyard?
在那种地方的感觉很棒  对不对
It feels good to go somewhere like that, right?
一个无人知晓  没人能找到你的地方
A place no one knows about, where no one can get to you.
这里对我来说也是一样
Well, that's what this place is for me.
没事的  没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
能给他看看你的证件吗  布莱克特工
Would you please show him your credentials, Agent Blake?
中情局埃米莉·布莱克特工
Agent Emily Blake, CIA.
我为我之前在你家里不得已的行为表示道歉
I'm sorry that had to happen in front of you at the house.
当时她是被派去家里保护你的
She was stationed at the house to protect you...
就是让你不受后来那个男人的伤害
from exactly the man who ended up coming,
那个声称是你父亲的人
the man who said he was your dad.
真的吗
Really?
联调局和中情局
通缉  卡尼尔·乌提斯
为了保护国家  这些年我结下许多仇人
I've made enemies defending America over the years.
最糟糕的是  这个人
Worst part is that this particular one
勾起了你对父亲的回忆
dredged up the memory of your father.
事实上  麦克
The truth is, Mikey,
尽管你或许想相信这些
despite what you may want to believe,
可你父亲在七年前就已经去世了
your father died seven years ago.
喂
Yeah.
我是迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
This is Michael Scofield.
我们正聊起你的事呢
We were just talking about you.
我现在给你最后一次活命的机会
I'm giving you one last chance to save your life.
把孩子交给我  不然我不敢保证
Hand the boy over or I can't be held responsible
接下去会发生什么事
for what happens next.
你是在威胁会杀死我吗
Are you threatening my life?
如果你不把他交给我的话
Only if you don't hand him over.
我永远不会交出我的儿子
I'd never hand over my son.
他自始至终都不是你的儿子
He's not your son and never was.
离我爸爸远点  听见了吗
Stay away from my dad, you hear?
离他远点
Stay away!
好孩子
Good boy.
他叫那个人爸爸
He called him Dad.
雅各布
Jacob.
不  他只是在对他洗脑
No, he's-he's brainwashing him, that's all.
你是对的  那样的人
Man like that, you're right.
他只配去死
He deserves to die.
他在哪
Where is he?
波塞冬在哪
Where is Poseidon?
我来解决他
He'll be dealt with.
等等  稍等一下
Wait, hang on, hang on, hang on, man.
如果你被抓了
If you get caught--
如果他被抓了  他就得回监狱
if he gets caught, he's going back to the pen.
-别这样  别  -我不会...
- Come on, come on. - ‭I'm not...
如果我不这么做呢
And if I don't do it?
小逃犯  我想让你恢复自由和清白
Criminy, I want you free and clear,
如果这是唯一的办法  那只能是由我去做
and if that's the only way to do it, then I got to be the one that does it.
斯科菲尔德不会这么做
Scofield ain't gonna do it.
他没有杀人的天分
He don't got the killing gene.
没人会被抓
No one is getting caught.
这点我明确表态
There's a very specific order to this.
莎拉  我要你保障林肯的安全
Sara, I want you to make sure Linc's safe
不能让他有事
and out of harm's way.
维普  茶包哥去帮我们找一张"百搭牌"[外援]
Whip, T-Bag, you're gonna collect a wild card for us.
一张雅各布都不知道它存在的"百搭牌"[外援]
One that Jacob doesn't know is out there.
我要去他们老巢  这一切开始的源头
I'm gonna go to the nest, where this all started,
那个隐藏着所有秘密的地方
where the secrets lay hidden,
那个终将血债血偿的正确所在
and where blood will finally be spilled in its rightful place.
我刚接的来自斯科菲尔德的那通电话
The call I just got from Scofield--
我想知道它是从哪打来的
I want to know where it came from.
正在向你发送地点信息
Location data coming to you right now.
他们在某个偏远的地方
Middle of nowhere.
向东北方向移动  然后手机关机了
Started moving northeast and the phone was shut off.
也许是扔了
Maybe tossed.
北纽约动物园
你和你那该死的动物园  斯科菲尔德
You and your damn zoo, Scofield.
我要彻底搞明白
I'm gonna find out once and for all
当时你究竟在那里干什么
what you were really doing there.
当时你究竟在计划什么
What you were really planning.
然后我会杀了你
And then I'm gonna kill you.
你的事我全都知道
I know everything about you.
连你最平常的小动作都知道
Even your most mundane actions.
比如动物园  你和动物园算怎么回事
Like the zoo. What's with you and the zoo?
敌人
敌人犯
我告诉自己  那个将其计划
I had to know everything about the man
纹在身上的人  我得了解他的一切
who wore his plans on his skin.
看似一览无遗  实则神秘莫测
In plain sight, yet so mysterious.
你的敌人犯
永远别  你的敌人犯
永远别在你的敌人犯
实权的秘诀
The secret to real power
在于决不违背你的意愿
is to never betray your intentions.
深藏不露
To wear nothing on your sleeve,
也决不让任何人看见你的脸
and to never let anyone see your face.
伊萨卡大学
我永远会先你一步
I'll always be a step ahead of you.
我能从你的眼神中看穿一切
I can see everything in your eyes.
怎么
What?
我解开了眼睛里的密码
I decrypted the code from the eyes.
是引用了拿破仑的一句话
It's a quote from Napoleon.
引用了什么
What quote?
"永远别在你的敌人犯错误时打断他们"
"Never interrupt your enemy when he's making a mistake."
眼神背后的心机才是关键
It's what's behind the eyes that counts.
构建面部轮廓比对
构建匹配
身份匹配已获取
-喂  -我觉得应该告诉你
- Yeah. - Thought you should know
我正看着你的秘密服务器
I'm looking at your closed servers right now.
你的硬盘在我手上
I'm holding your hard drives in my hand.
你所有的秘密通讯
All your secret communications.
足够让你永久出局了
Enough to send you away forever.
不赖嘛  迈克尔
Bravo, Michael.
无论你是怎么进去的  真不赖
However you got in there, bravo.
你把我骗来动物园  你就能进我办公室
You sent me to the zoo so you could get into my office.
但我俩都清楚你的威胁没有力度
But you and I both know your threat's a hollow one,
因为你知道我手上有样东西
because you know I've got something
对你来说更有价值  你的儿子
that's even more valuable to you: your son.
所以我们又回归博弈论了
So we're back to game theory.
我们是一起合作  达成交易
Do we work together, make a trade
然后各取所需呢
so we both get what we want?
还是你要耍花招呢
Or are you gonna try something underhanded?
-你知道我会的  -我也会
- You know I will. - As will I.
所以不如放下此事  做笔交易
So why don't we cut past that and make a deal?
行  迈克尔  就那样办
Sure, Michael. Yeah, let's do that.
老船坞
Old shipyard.
A仓库
Warehouse A.
明天下午五点
5:00 P.M. Tomorrow.
行
Fine.
抱歉
Excuse me?
我老公他哥  林肯·布鲁斯
My brother-in-law... did-did Lincoln Burrows,
被送到其他病房了吗
did he get moved?
没有  女士  他自行出院了
No, ma'am. He checked himself out.
-他流了很多血  -我知道
- He was down a lot of blood. ‭- I know.
我们阻止过他  但如果病人坚持
We tried to stop him, but if a patient insists,
如果他们力所能及的话  我们只能放人
if it's within their power, we have to let 'em go.
这位是巴拉德医生  他负责手术
This is Dr. Ballard. He did the surgery.
你好  莎拉·斯科菲尔德
‭Hi, Sara Scofield,
我是个伊萨卡的内科医生
I'm an internist, actually, up at Ithaca.
你知道我老公他哥可能去了哪吗
Do you have any idea where my brother-in-law might have gone?
不知道
No idea.
好吧
Right.
手指湖区发生什么事了  你知道吗
What happened up in Finger Lakes, do you know?
同一地区同一时间的还送来了
Another gunshot victim came in from the same area
另一个枪伤患者
at the same time.
我老公他哥是独自一人  肯定是巧合
My brother-in-law was alone. It must be a coincidence.
但谢谢了
But thank you.
我要走了  我已经尽我所能了
Well, I'm heading out. I've done what I can.
他在三楼  用着生命维持系统
He's on life support up on three,
但说实话  我觉得他撑不到早上
but candidly, I don't think he's making it till morning.
卢卡
Luca.
你害我还躲了你一阵
You had me running there for a bit,
还以为我干了什么坏事
thinking I'd done something wrong.
你就是干了
You did.
你骗了我  欠的十万美金不还
You stiffed me $100 grand.
不  那是用受害者的血换来的钱
Nah. It's blood money.
这种脏钱没有什么欠不欠的
No debts with blood money.
快说"我们两清了"
Say we're clear.
来舔哥呀  布鲁斯
Eat me, Burrows.
叫你快说"我们两清了"
Say we're clear.
我会多叫几个弟兄
I'm gonna get more guys.
然后哥看你接着逃得像丧家犬
And you'll be running again.
这次不行了
Not this time.
那些又是你朋友假扮的吗
Are those your fake friends again?
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
不  这次是真的
No. This time, they're real.
我们是联邦探员
Federal agents!
把手举起来
Hands where I can see 'em!
-举起手来  -布鲁斯
- Hands up! - Burrows!
现在照做
Do it now!
布鲁斯
Burrows!
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
我要找我儿子
I need to find my boy.
给
Here.
让
让我
让我死
他是个恶魔  还抓了我儿子
He's an evil man and he's got my son.
你肯定知道什么人  知道点什么
You've got to know someone. Something.
知道我能把我孩子救回来的办法
Someway I can get my boy back.
拜托
Please.
你确定我儿子在这里吗
You sure this is where my son is?
谢谢
Thank you.
没事了
It's all right.
杀人是不对的
Killing ain't right.
对  我读过《圣经》
Yeah, I read the Bible.
真的吗
You did?
我曾在旅店房间里大概翻了翻
You know, I scanned it once in a hotel room.
你有什么感悟吗
Well, what you gonna do?
除非某人罪有应得  否则别滥杀无辜
Don't kill anybody unless they really deserve it.
你读的肯定是《旧约》部分
Yeah, you must've read the Old Testament part.
以眼还眼  以牙还牙
An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth.
对  随你怎么说
Sure, whatever.
对  我只是想说
Yeah, I'm just saying,
有时候  一些众人皆知的恶棍
sometimes, certain-- certain sons of bitches,
就该用这种老办法铲除他们
they just need to be plain old eradicated.
没有他们这个世界会更好
World's just better minus them.
比如阿布·拉马尔
Like Abu Ramal.
但大部分情况下  杀人是不对的
But for the most part, you know, killing's just bad.
当然了
Yeah, absolutely.
除了波塞冬
Except Poseidon. ‭
-他也得死  -他得死
- Yeah, he's got to go, too. - Got to go.
我只是不想让你对我的看法
I just don't want you to get the wrong idea
-有误会  好吗  -好
- about me, okay? - ‭Okay.
你得像瑜伽师一样看问题  懂吗
You got to see it like the yogis, okay?
消除消极面以创造积极的一面
Destroying the negative to create the positive.
"湿婆之舞"之类的
"The dance of the Shivas"   and all that.
[湿婆是印度教的三大主神之一  是宇宙之王  湿婆之舞  是宇宙之舞  湿婆之舞是印度文化的象征]
抹杀黑暗  光明才能诞生
Murder the dark, so the-- the light can be born.
你是疯了吧
You're out of your damn tree, aren't you?
-现在你知道你是遗传谁的了  -真赞
- Now you know where you got it from. ‭- Great.
这里有个叫"蓝色夏威夷"的人吗
Is there a BlueHawaii in there?
在呢  别磨蹭了  进来吧
Yeah, don't just dillydally, come on in.
我猜你们这俩小混混是斯科菲尔德的人吧
I assume you two desperados are Scofield's guys.
是
Yeah.
他也把你们从监狱里救出来了吗
He get you out of prison, too?
不是
No.
不过我确实欠他人情
But I do owe him.
他把你从哪救出来的
Where'd he break you out of?
南美洲  巴兰基亚
Barranquilla, South America.
那里的人要把我生吞活剥
They were gonna eat my lunch down there,
谁让我长得这么俊俏呢
pretty boy like me.
斯科菲尔德同情我
Scofield took pity.
我猜是看到我有什么天赋  把我救了出去
Saw a talent in me, I guess. Got me out.
他说可能哪天用得着我的天赋
Said he might call on those talents some day in return,
而现在你们来了
and now here we are.
等我润个色  我就帮你们
Soon as I put the touches on this, I'm yours.
等得不耐烦了
Got bored waiting.
太厉害了
It's incredible.
重建了迪利广场  肯尼迪就是在那被刺杀的
Rebuild of Dealey Plaza, where JFK was shot.
这里是存书处
This here is a book depository.
这么纠结于细节  会让人疯掉的
Attention to detail like that, drive a man crazy.
看看我  我就是个窝在家的疯子
Look at me. I'm a crap house loon.
我总执着于重温过去
Excessive need to bring the past back to life.
让它变得真实
Make it real.
不过够了
But enough of that.
该干正经事了  对吧
Time for the real dance to begin, am I right?
我们会把他救回来的  好吗
We're going to get him back, okay?
你的"百搭牌"[外援]准备就绪
We got your wild card ready to go.
谢谢
Thank you.
是我该谢谢你
Me that should be thanking you.
一直以来  都是你罩着我
You brought me all this way.
是我们一起完成的
We did it together.
我们也会一起干下去
We'll be doing this together.
你给了我家人
You gave me family.
真的  谢谢你
Seriously, thank you.
说起家人...
Speaking of family...
我们出发吧
Let's go.
伊萨卡大学
请不要碰那个
Don't touch that, please.
现在绝不能碰
It's not an option right now.
我儿子在哪
Now where is my son?
你明知道  你问的问题
You ask questions you know there isn't a chance in hell
我绝对不会回答
I'm gonna answer.
所以我们又回归博弈论了
So we're back to the game.
真相是  我们一直在博弈
The truth is, we never left.
你手里没有王牌
You're not holding the cards.
-而我有  -是吗
- I am. - ‭Are you?
世界上所有的执法部门都在找你
Every law agency in the world is looking for you.
你这处境可不像是能对我施压的样子
Doesn't sound like a position of power to me.
如果我被抓了
If I get arrested,
那些服务器就会被发布出去
those servers will be released,
你所做的一切都会曝光
and everything you've done will be exposed.
我会找到它们  销毁掉
I'll find them. I'll destroy them.
我说了
Like I said,
王牌在我手里
I'm holding the cards.
真是出人意料啊
Didn't expect that.
这未免有失你身份  迈克尔
It's beneath you, Michael.
放他走
Let him go!
玩这招  我早料到了
Now that, I expected.
谢谢
Thank you.
还是把枪放下吧  女士
How about we drop it, lady?
你以为我就想不到这一手吗
You don't think I expected this?
我们可以一直这样玩下去
We could do this all day.
应急方案层出不穷
Play contingency after contingency.
但你真想这样吗
But do you really want to do that?
不  大卫  该死
No! David. Dammit!
退后  不然我现在就杀了他
Back off, or I kill him right now.
这肯定是你的最后一招了吧
And that must be the last of your contingencies.
感谢你的倾力表演  迈克尔
Thank you so much for showing me, Michael.
对了
Oh, yeah.
还应该告诉你  我打给了联调局
You should also know I called the FBI.
一条匿名线报称
An anonymous tip saying
卡尼尔·乌提斯会出现在这个仓库里
that Kaniel Outis would be at this warehouse.
继续清场  去第二个地点
Keep clear. Moving to second position.
听着  他们进来了
Okay, they're in the building.
没时间了
There's no more time.
交出那些硬盘
The hard drives,
否则我们就要开枪射你的"棋子们"[同伙]了
or we'll start shooting your pieces.
把男孩交出来
Hand over the damn boy!
闭嘴
Shut up.
女士  把枪放下然后走开
Lady, put the gun down, walk away,
否则我对接下来的事情可不负责
as I cannot be held accountable for what's about to happen.
他要动  你就开枪
He moves, shoot him!
我曾在酒吧斗殴时杀过一个人
I killed a guy in a bar fight once.
当时他对我的妞儿爆粗口  而哥秒杀了他
He was talking yang to my girl. Took me one second to do it.
别出手
Don't do it!
你该听他的  他可是个非常聪明的人
You should listen to him. He's a very smart man.
我是在跟你说话  维普
I'm talking to you, Whip.
不值得为这事去死  这是我的战斗
It's not worth dying for. This is my fight!
这是我们的战斗
This is our fight.
我们费尽心血  绝不能让这混蛋得逞
We've come too far to let this son of a bitch win.
这本就不在计划之内
This wasn't the plan!
别出手
Don't do it!
有些混蛋总得让他们滚蛋
Some sons of bitches just got to go!
我们是唯一能出手的人  对不对  爸
We're the only ones who could do it. Ain't that right, Pa?
大卫
David!
有种试试
Try me.
维普
Whip!
不
No!
维普
‭Whip.
Whip.
维普  计划本不是这样的
Whip. This wasn't the plan.
大卫  挺住
David, stay with me.
挺住  儿子  挺住
Stay with me, boy. Stay with me.
交出硬盘  快点
The hard drives. Now.
有我在  没事的  有我在
I got him. It's okay, I got him.
好
All right.
在那边
It's that way.
保持冷静  小子
Keep it calm, boy.
-保持冷静  -如果他也想逞英雄
- Stay calm. - If he tries to play hero, too,
就杀了他
execute him.
大卫
David...
你开枪打了他  你个贱人
You shot him, you bitch.
他本就不该惹老娘
He shouldn't have tried me.
-举起手来  -别动
- Hands up! - Freeze!
快照做  我们是联邦探员
Do it now! Federal agents!
把手放到我能看见的地方
Hands where I can see them!
我...
I'm...
我没事  我得...
I'm good. I got to s...
看见你的脸
see your face.
别动  举起手来
Freeze! Get your hands up!
走好  儿子
Go easy, son.
近来可好
How we doing?
比你要好
Better than you.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你还好吗
You okay?
前面  就放在下一个隔间
Up ahead, in the next bay.
这电话我来接
I'll take that call.
找到了  迈克尔  救出我们儿子了
We got him, Michael. We got our boy.
恭喜你啊
Good news for you.
但现在你也没必要给我我想要的东西了
But now you've got no reason to give me what I want.
这对你来说也算是个坏消息
which kind of makes it bad news for you.
联邦探员
Federal agents!
你个贱人
You son of a bitch.
那间小屋
The cabin.
盖恩斯的外套
Gaines' jacket.
摄像头  拍下我的样子
Camera, taking my picture.
空包弹[即没有弹头]
Blanks.
刚才你是故意让我把枪从你手上抢走
You wanted me to take the gun from you back there.
你比我原想的要厉害啊
You're better than I thought.
把我犯下的谋杀罪再栽赃给我
Re-framing me for the murder I actually committed.
是你栽赃给我的那个
The one you framed me for.
迈克尔  搬走尸体
Michael, pick up the body,
清理现场  什么痕迹都不能留
make it look like it never happened.
真是天才  真的
Genius, really.
可惜没人会相信
But no one will ever go for it.
真相是你给世人展现的样子
The truth is whatever you tell people it is.
你教我的
You taught me that.
可惜两分钟后联邦探员就会赶到这里
Too bad the feds'll be here in two minutes,
看到你布置的场景
see your little diorama here,
就会知道这一切都是假象
and know it's all bull.
只是那时这些都不在了
Except none of this will be here.
我也不会在
And neither will I.
大型卡车
王八蛋
Bastard!
这是为过去这七年
This is for the last seven years.
别动  举起双手
Freeze! Get your hands up!
举起双手
Put 'em up!
是他  是卡尼尔·乌提斯
It's him! It's Kaniel Outis!
幸好你们来了
Thank God you're here.
谢天谢地
Thank God!
Thank God.
谢天谢地
手举起来
Hands up!
幸好你们及时赶到了
Thank God you guys got here when you did,
我的感激难以言表
that's all I can say.
否则他就会...
I mean, he would have...
否则我现在已经是死人了
I'd be dead right now.
如果你们同意的话
Look, if it's okay with you guys,
我想回家  收拾一下
I'd like to go home, clean myself up a bit.
你们也能想到  今天有够漫长的
As you can imagine, it's been a long day.
-可以  -谢谢
- That's okay. - Thank you.
雅各布·安东·奈斯吗
Jacob Anton Ness?
有事吗
Can I help you?
你因涉嫌谋杀哈伦·盖恩斯被捕了
You're under arrest for the participation in the murder of Harlan Gaines.
如果你是指那些荒唐的布景...
If you're talking about that nonsense in there... ‭
我们是指在你大学的办公室里发现的
We're talking about blood evidence found in your office
血迹证据
at the university.
只有你有进入权限的办公室
An office only you have access to.
哈伦·盖恩斯的血迹
Harlan Gaines' blood.
"鲜血"终将洒在它应在的位置
And blood will finally be spilled in its rightful place.
[那个终将"血"债"血"偿的正确所在]
什么  怎么会...
What? How...
这是那晚谋杀丢失的画面
These are the missing frames from the night of the killing.
是被波塞冬删去的画面
The ones Poseidon edited out.
没错  我当时在场  这一点我从未否认
Yes, I was there. I've never denied it.
他逼我去的...
He forced me to...
就为了陷害我
so he could frame me.
所以你物品上的血迹证据
So the blood evidence found in your belongings
是他让你处理尸体时留下的
was because he tasked you with disposing of the body.
没错
Correct.
加上在他大学办公室里发现的
And with the revelation of the additional blood evidence
另外的血迹证据
found in his office at the university,
恰好佐证了你的说法  对吗
it neatly supports your theory, doesn't it?
证明了他当时在场
That he was there.
证明了开枪的人  是他
That he was the gunman.
我想我只有一个问题问你
I guess I would have one question for you.
-我是中情局局长  -我知道
- I'm director of the CIA. - I'm aware of that.
所以我才直接把证据发电子邮件给你
That's why I sent you the e-mail with the evidence directly.
我的问题是
My question is...
谁知道你现在是不是也在操控我
would you be manipulating me, too?
我能怎么操控你
How would I do that?
这个...
Well...
你要是仔细研究这些证据
you look too closely at this evidence--
照片元数据  腐化的血迹证据
metadata in the pictures, degraded blood evidence--
也许会发现些问题
you might find some problems.
就看你有多想仔细地研究这些证据了
Depends how motivated you are to look closely.
波塞冬杀死了你的副局
Poseidon killed your deputy director.
他是你们机构中滞留多年的毒瘤
He was a cancer inside your agency for years.
我让你看到了他的真面目
I've shown you his face!
镇定
Now, calm down.
你要知道我们抓到了奈斯先生的同伙
You should know that we have Mr. Ness' accomplice,
安德鲁·尼尔森  已被拘禁
Andrew Nelson, in custody,
多亏了你哥哥
thanks to your brother,
看完你的电子邮件
Once we saw your e-mail,
我们就审讯了他
we interrogated him.
他对"21号空间"的阴谋供认不讳
He's fully disclosed 21-Void's conspiracy
包括他曾把谋杀哈伦·盖恩斯的事栽赃给你
to frame you for the murder of Harlan Gaines
隐瞒你的身份  给了你一个新名字
and bury your identity by giving you a new one:
卡尼尔·乌提斯
Kaniel Outis.
所以呢
What does that mean?
所以...
It means...
你自由了  斯科菲尔德先生
...you're free to go, Mr. Scofield.
你不知道我等别人叫我这个名字等了多久
You don't know how long I've waited to hear someone call me that.
还有一件事
One other thing.
你的这整个计划极其周密
The level of ingenuity that you displayed with all of this--
我们需要你这样的人才
we could use a person like that.
但我现在不想找工作
I am not looking for a job.
好吧
Right.
你倒是可以为我做一件事
There is one thing you can do for me.
你喜欢这里吗
You liking it here?
感觉很奇怪
It's strange.
重获新生
Being alive again.
不再四处逃亡
Not running.
是啊
Yeah.
我也曾经四处逃亡
I've been running, too.
我知道
I know.
你为什么联系她
Why'd you call her?
因为我知道你不会
Because I knew you wouldn't.
真正奇怪的是...
What's really strange is...
这一切竟然真的成了
things actually working out.
是啊
Yeah.
好兄弟
I love you.
I love you, too.
他更擅长让自己卷入...
He's better at getting himself into...
他很固执
He's stubborn.
-嗨  -亲爱的
- Hey. - Hey, babe.
伊利诺斯州
乔利埃特
福克斯河州立监狱
我还真不习惯有人笑着进来
Not used to guys smiling, coming in here.
因为我并不打算长住
Yeah, just not planning on sticking around long,
就这样
that's all.
好吧
Yeah, right.
好好享受吧
Have a good one.
不  不  不
No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no! No! No!
狱警  狱警
Guard! Guard!